# STEVE HANSON SOFTWARE DEVELOPER





### **OBJECTIVE**

Over the past seven years, I have gained a breadth of experience working at companies ranging from large corporations to small startups. I am a creative, team-oriented problem-solver and have consistently been a top performer in my past roles. I would love the opportunity to see if I might be a fit for your team!



# **EXPERIENCE**

## **Lead Software Developer** | StudioHop Fitness

2015-2018

Rails 5, React, Angular 1 & 2, AWS S3, Ionic 3, API integrations, REST Developed and maintained Rails application for early-stage SaaS startup.

#### Lead Software Developer | Spacetime

2015-2017

Rails 5, React, Angular, Heroku, ElasticSearch

Developed web applications for SaaS startups. Notable clients included StudioHop (see above), Steadkey, and Keyzie.

#### Web Developer | Oven Bits

2014-2015

Rails, Ember, Heroku

Notable clients included Lays, National Breast Cancer Foundation, Brainspace.

#### Senior Technical Consultant | Credera

2013-2014

Java 7/8, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Scala, Tomcat, PHP

Worked on e-commerce stores for Freeman Co and Pep Boys, mentored developers.

#### **Software Engineer |** American Airlines

2011-2013

Java, Spring MVC, Spring Web Flow, Hibernate, JUnit, Websphere

Pitched project to CIO and CEO with 11 other new hires and implemented as tech lead. The project, AwardMap, received favorable review and is <u>still live</u>.



# **EDUCATION**

# **B.S. Computer Engineering, Minor Math** | Texas A&M

2007-2011

Graduated with 4.0 GPA



#### **SKILLS**

**Back-End:** Ruby on Rails, Heroku, ElasticSearch, Node.js, Express, Java **Front-End:** React, React Native, Angular (1, 2+), Ember, Modern JS, SCSS